<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Blue</string>

    <string name="menu_play">PLAY</string>
    <string name="menu_strategy">PLAN</string>
    <string name="menu_help">Help</string>

    <string name="btn_shuffle">Shuffle</string>
    <string name="btn_next_game">Next game</string>
    <string name="btn_clear">Clear</string>
    <string name="btn_restart">Restart</string>
    <string name="btn_reset">New</string>
    <string name="btn_help">Help</string>
    <string name="btn_exit">Exit</string>
    <string name="btn_play">Play</string>
    <string name="btn_file">File</string>
    <string name="btn_save">Save</string>
    <string name="btn_load">Load</string>
    <string name="btn_delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="btn_export">Export</string>
    <string name="btn_strategy">Plan</string>
    <string name="btn_backward">Backward</string>
    <string name="btn_forward">Forward</string>
    <string name="btn_cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="btn_ok">OK</string>

    <string name="ask_restart">Restart the game?</string>
    <string name="ask_clear">Clear play strategy?</string>
    <string name="ask_reset">Reset with a new game?</string>
    <string name="ask_next_game">Go to the next game?</string>
    <string name="ask_exit">Do you want really to exit?</string>

    <string name="game_">Game: %1$s</string>
    <string name="game_list">Games</string>
    <string name="game_over">Game over</string>
    <string name="congrats">Congratulations!</string>


<string name="help">
Blue is a a card game, inspired after the game "Blue Moon" created by
Tim Lister (see www.catb.org/~esr/bluemoon/bluemoon.html).
BR
The purpose of the game is to order the 52 cards of the deck.
BR
A card can be moved to an empty place provided one of the following two
conditions holds:
[1] there is a card in the
place to the left and this card has the same suit of the card that is 
being moved and value exactly one less than it; 
[2] there is a card in the
place to the right and this card has the same suit of the card that is 
being moved and value exactly one more than it.
BR
Before you start moving the cards you can plan a playing strategy: the
program starts in PLAN mode. In this mode you can rearrange the aces in the first
column, by dragging them up and down to swap their positions.
You can also mark runs of cards with the same
suit. Start with a card of that suit and drag it to the left or to the
right.
BR
Once you are happy with the positions of the aces and the suit runs, turn
the program into PLAY mode (with the first menu), and move the cards.
BR
The program keeps tracks of the moves and, while in PLAY mode, you can go 
back and forth with a up or down drag gesture on the aces column.
BR
You can go back to PLAN mode and change your strategy, even if you have already 
moved some cards. However, you can swap aces only if you have not yet made any move.
BR
The game is over when the cards form four ordered sequences, one for each suit.
BR
BR
Tap MENU dot, in the middle center, to open the menu dialog.
The six menus are:
BR
"Play/Strategy" switch (in the middle)
BR
"File" dialog
BR
"Restart" the play
BR
"New Game"
BR
"Help" 
BR
"Exit"
BR
BR

Games are stored in the internal storage.
From the "File" dialog you can store the current game, load a stored game, and 
copy a game to the sdcard. Select the game tapping on its name (the long number).
You can also import a game from the sdcard to the internal storage.
BR
The app comes with a set of 36 pre-installed games.
Each of these games has a solution.

</string>

</resources>
